<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Blog EN</title>
	<atom:link href="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 11 Apr 2014 15:08:24 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=3.4</generator>
		<item>
		<title>Card acceptance for UK online stores made easy</title>
		<link>http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/card-acceptance-for-uk-online-stores-made-easy/</link>
		<comments>http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/card-acceptance-for-uk-online-stores-made-easy/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 11 Apr 2014 12:54:53 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Deborah Penna</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[PrestaShop Partners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=16559</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Many small businesses are still reluctant to accept credit and debit card payments on their online store, being somewhat intimidated by the process. And it is easy to understand why: getting a merchant account application processed and accepted can prove &#8230; <a href="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/card-acceptance-for-uk-online-stores-made-easy/" rel="nofollow" class="more-link">Read more<span class="meta-nav"></span></a>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Many small businesses are still reluctant to accept credit and debit card payments on their online store, being somewhat intimidated by the process. And it is easy to understand why: getting a merchant account application processed and accepted can prove to be quite a daunting and lengthy task, and the possibility that your request will be declined is always a concern.</p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-16683" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/04/card-acceptance-uk-online-stores-made-easy1.jpg" alt="" width="578" height="278" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span id="more-16559"></span>However, accepting and facilitating credit card payments on your online store is a must and a necessary step towards boosting your sales and increasing your customer-base. Now, let’s go over the different factors to take into consideration and introduce you to a simple way to accept debit and credit card payments for your online store.</p>
<h2>Why should your business accept credit card payments?</h2>
<p>Simply put, businesses that do not yet accept credit and/or debit cards are missing out on increasing their online sales and profit.</p>
<p>Studies show that the majority of <strong>customers prefer to pay by credit and debit card</strong> and will be more likely to make a purchase or increase their average spending, when given the convenience of purchasing by card.</p>
<p>In addition, accepting credit cards will <strong>encourage impulse shopping.</strong> Do you offer discounts and/or promotions? Make it simple for your customers to take advantage of your store’s special offers.</p>
<p>In the UK, about <strong>“91% of the adult population have a debit card and 61% a credit card”.</strong> With online spending using debit cards reaching £35 billion compared to £34 billion on credit cards, <a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/business-23149647" target="_blank">according to the UK Cards Association.</a></p>
<p><strong>In summary, these are some of the major benefits of accepting card payments:</strong><br />
- Boost sales<br />
- Attract more customers that prefer to use this payment option<br />
- Increase customers’ spending and impulse shopping<br />
- Improve your cash flow</p>
<h3>How to get started</h3>
<p>To start accepting credit and debit cards, you will need to set up:<br />
- A Merchant Account<br />
- A Payment Gateway, linking your online store to your Merchant Account</p>
<p>Some business information, to enable the Payment Processor to assess your application, should be provided: the type of business you&#8217;re in, sales revenue, number of transactions</p>
<h3>The best solution available to UK Small- and Medium-Sized Businesses</h3>
<p>PaymentSense has quickly become the card processing partner of choice for many small- and medium-sized businesses, thanks to their:</p>
<p>- Swift Merchant Account approval process &#8211; meaning your online store could be accepting card payments within 24 hours, following approval<br />
- Affordable, fixed price plans<br />
- Dedicated customer service<br />
- No long-term agreement requirements</p>
<p><img class="size-full wp-image-16682 aligncenter" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/04/PaymentSense.png" alt="" width="159" height="45" /></p>
<p><strong>PaymentSense is the UK’s largest Merchant Services Provider</strong> servicing over 30,000 SMEs and their payment module &#8211; compatible with v1.4.0.1 &#8211; v1.6.0.6 &#8211; is now available to UK PrestaShop merchants, native in the software or, for free, on PrestaShop’s Official Marketplace.</p>
<p>Download the <a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/payments-gateways-prestashop-modules/8869-paymentsense.html" target="_blank">PaymentSense module</a> now and never miss a sale again!</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/card-acceptance-for-uk-online-stores-made-easy/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ecommerce 101: 25 Terms Every Online Merchant Should Know</title>
		<link>http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/ecommerce-101-25-terms-every-online-merchant-should-know/</link>
		<comments>http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/ecommerce-101-25-terms-every-online-merchant-should-know/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2014 15:47:45 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Julie Liu</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Tips and Advice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=16532</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[As technology advances, words are created to describe new ideas and concepts. Having trouble keeping up with all these new technological words? Don’t worry! Today we’re helping you build your ecommerce vocabulary with 25 terms every online merchant should know. &#8230; <a href="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/ecommerce-101-25-terms-every-online-merchant-should-know/" rel="nofollow" class="more-link">Read more<span class="meta-nav"></span></a>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As technology advances, words are created to describe new ideas and concepts. Having trouble keeping up with all these new technological words? Don’t worry! Today we’re helping you build your ecommerce vocabulary with 25 terms every online merchant should know.</p>
<p>We’re simplifying and demystifying these words to introduce the language of ecommerce. Soon you’ll understand all these fancy ecommerce jargon and shortened abbreviations.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-16533" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/04/EN_Ecommerce-101-25-terms-every-online-merchant-should-know.jpg" alt="" width="578" height="278" /></p>
<p><span id="more-16532"></span></p>
<h4><span style="color: #800000">1. Back Office / Back End</span></h4>
<p>Accessed with a username and password through the admin page, this part of the ecommerce software allows merchants to manage and operate online stores</p>
<h4><span style="color: #800000">2. Big Data</span></h4>
<p>The name given to large amounts of customer information collected through ecommerce. There is a growing trend and interest in leveraging this data to make smarter business decisions.</p>
<h4><span style="color: #800000">3. Cache</span></h4>
<p>Temporary data a computer stores to help websites load quicker. To clear your cache is to reload a web page with new data generally to see changes made during web development</p>
<h4><span style="color: #800000">4. Call-to-Action (CTA)</span></h4>
<p>Image, text, or combination that encourages the reader to perform an action and drive conversions.</p>
<h4><span style="color: #800000">5. (Shopping) Cart Abandonment, Abandoned Carts</span></h4>
<p>This occurs when customers add products to their carts but leave your online store before making a purchase.</p>
<h4><span style="color: #800000">6. Checkout Funnel</span></h4>
<p>The checkout process portrayed as a funnel to emulate the loss of customer conversions at each step. Checkout processes include 5-page, 1- page, easy, guest and account creation.</p>
<h4><span style="color: #800000">7. Conversion Rate</span></h4>
<p><img class="size-medium wp-image-16538 aligncenter" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/04/conversionrate-300x43.png" alt="" width="300" height="43" /></p>
<p>A successful conversion is the completion of an activity – ranging from newsletter signups to purchases.</p>
<h4><span style="color: #800000">8. CPC, CPM, PPC, CPA</span></h4>
<p>Each of these are <em> pricing models </em> for online advertising.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 60px">● <strong>CPC</strong> (Cost per Click)<br />
● <strong>CPM</strong> (Cost per Mille / Thousand Impressions)<br />
● <strong>PPC</strong> (Pay per Click)<br />
● <strong>CPA</strong> (Cost per Action)</p>
<h4><span style="color: #800000">9. Digital Products (Downloadable Products)</span></h4>
<p>Digital products include: EBooks, Music, Movies, Programs, Apps, and PrestaShop modules. In ecommerce it is the sale of intellectual property. PrestaShop allows you to sell these types of products &#8212; for free!</p>
<h4><span style="color: #800000">10. Ergonomics</span></h4>
<p>The visual appeal and refined usability of your website. Ergonomic websites are error free, intuitive, and easy to use.</p>
<h4><span style="color: #800000">11. Front Office (Store Front / Front End)</span></h4>
<p>It is the side of your ecommerce website that customers interact with – product displays, account creation and checkout process.</p>
<h4><span style="color: #800000">12. Inbound (Backlinks) &amp; Outbound Link</span></h4>
<p style="padding-left: 60px">● Inbound Links – links <strong>from </strong>other websites that <strong>lead to</strong> a page on your ecommerce site<br />
● Outbound links – links that <strong>lead to </strong>another website <strong>from </strong>your ecommerce site</p>
<p>Both are important in increasing SEO and should be anchored by<span style="text-decoration: underline"> good key words</span></p>
<h4><span style="color: #800000">13. Keywords | Keyword</span></h4>
<p>A word or phrase that 1) customers are searching 2) accurately describes your company 3) search engines use to help customers find your online store</p>
<h4><span style="color: #800000">14. KPI (Key Performance Indicators)</span></h4>
<p>What are the goals for your ecommerce site? KPI’s are stats and ratios that help you measure your success in reaching your goals. Discover the <a href="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/the-10-best-kpis-every-online-store-owner-should-keep-an-eye-on/" target="_blank">top 10 KPI&#8217;s for online merchants</a>.</p>
<h4><span style="color: #800000">15. Logistics</span></h4>
<p>Logistics covers the offline aspect to ecommerce – it includes the transport of goods (both from distributors and to customers), packaging orders, and customer support.</p>
<h4><span style="color: #800000">16. Merchant Account</span></h4>
<p>The account you open with payment processors that holds the incoming funds from credit card companies. Once approved, funds are deposited into your bank account.</p>
<h4><span style="color: #800000">17. Mobile Commerce (M-commerce)</span></h4>
<p>Ecommerce conducted through wireless devices such as cell phones and tablets</p>
<h4><span style="color: #800000">18. Multi-Channel Retailing</span></h4>
<p>Selling through multiple channels – ecommerce (online sales), with a brick and mortar store and taking phone orders.</p>
<h4><span style="color: #800000">19. Multi Store</span></h4>
<p>Linking 2 or more online stores to the same back office (native in PrestaShop) – use multi-store to separate price catalogs or multiple product lines</p>
<h4><span style="color: #800000">20. Payment Processors | Payment Gateways</span></h4>
<p>Both allow ecommerce merchants to processes payments from sales. They verify the card information with credit card companies who then approve the transaction.</p>
<h4><span style="color: #800000">21. Responsive</span></h4>
<p>Websites that allow users to view and use the website easily on all screen sizes. Buttons/ text become larger and layouts adjust to fit within the screen. Still not clear? Check out this infographic that explains <a href="http://edlea.com/blog/responsive-cereal/" target="_blank">responsive with cereal</a>.</p>
<h4><span style="color: #800000">22. SEO (Search Engine Optimization)</span></h4>
<p>Industry standards for creating content and web development to help search engines associate your website with relevant keywords</p>
<h4><span style="color: #800000">23. Traffic</span></h4>
<p>The amount of visitors to your online store &#8211; similar to foot traffic in a brick and mortar</p>
<h4><span style="color: #800000">24. UI &amp; UX</span></h4>
<p style="padding-left: 60px"><strong>● UI (User Interface)</strong> – Tools customers use in ecommerce. i.e. catalog, shopping cart, and checkout process<br />
●<strong> UX (User Experience)</strong> – The Look and feel of your online store.</p>
<p>Cereal is used to explain <a href="http://cl.ly/AX4l/o" target="_blank">UI and UX</a>.</p>
<h4><span style="color: #800000">25. Web Hosting</span></h4>
<p>Where data for your ecommerce site is stored. This network of computers allow customers to access the information needed to load your website on their computer.</p>
<p>___________</p>
<p>What other words do you think ecommerce merchants should know? Define and list them in the comments below. Already running an online store? What words do you think all PrestaShop merchants should know?</p>
<p>Not an online merchant? Get ready to start your online store by trying our <a href="http://www.prestashop.com/en/demo" target="_blank">Demo</a>. Or jump right in and <a href="http://www.prestashop.com/en/download" target="_blank">Download </a>PrestaShop &#8212; the best open-source ecommerce software &#8212; to get started today!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/ecommerce-101-25-terms-every-online-merchant-should-know/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>PrestaShop World Tour: Landed in Australia, an E-commerce Paradise!</title>
		<link>http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/prestashop-world-tour-landed-in-australia-an-e-commerce-paradise/</link>
		<comments>http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/prestashop-world-tour-landed-in-australia-an-e-commerce-paradise/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2014 15:30:54 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Quentin Audrain</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[PrestaShop World Tour]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=16505</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Australia is 12th largest economy in the world and one of the fastest growing e-commerce markets. There was no way we couldn’t make a stop in Australia! We had the great pleasure of meeting Stuart, the entrepreneur behind InFrontTech, the &#8230; <a href="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/prestashop-world-tour-landed-in-australia-an-e-commerce-paradise/" rel="nofollow" class="more-link">Read more<span class="meta-nav"></span></a>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Australia is 12th largest economy in the world and one of the fastest growing e-commerce markets. There was no way we couldn’t make a stop in Australia!</p>
<p>We had the great pleasure of meeting Stuart, the entrepreneur behind <a href="http://infronttech.com.au/" target="_blank">InFrontTech</a>, the security company based in Sydney.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-16507" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/04/PrestaShop-Australia.jpg" alt="" width="579" height="391" /></p>
<p><span id="more-16505"></span>To prove that Australia is an important e-commerce market, you should know that residents there are spending an average of $2,108 a year online. It’s more than anywhere else in the world.</p>
<p>In 2013, the e-commerce space was valued at more than $37 billion, one the most important in the world, especially if you consider that there are <strong>only</strong> 24 million people living in Australia.</p>
<p>Enough chatting, time to meet Stuart to talk about this super interesting market&#8230; Let’s Go!<br />
<iframe src="//player.vimeo.com/video/91518843" width="500" height="281" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<p><strong>Next Stop</strong>: Buenos Aires!</p>
<p>Want your city and PrestaShop store to be featured next? Leave us a comment or give us a shout out using the hashtag<strong> #PSWorldTour</strong> on <a href="https://twitter.com/prestashop" target="_blank">Twitter</a>!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/prestashop-world-tour-landed-in-australia-an-e-commerce-paradise/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>25 Simple Ideas to make your First Sale Online</title>
		<link>http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/25-simple-ideas-to-make-your-first-sale-online/</link>
		<comments>http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/25-simple-ideas-to-make-your-first-sale-online/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2014 15:03:37 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Julie Liu</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Tips and Advice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=16492</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[You’ve poured your heart and soul into uploading products, writing product descriptions, and configuring your online store. You are now rewarded with an ecommerce site that is open for business. But what now? How do you go about getting your &#8230; <a href="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/25-simple-ideas-to-make-your-first-sale-online/" rel="nofollow" class="more-link">Read more<span class="meta-nav"></span></a>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>You’ve poured your heart and soul into uploading products, writing product descriptions, and configuring your online store. You are now rewarded with an ecommerce site that is open for business. But what now? How do you go about getting your first customer? Where do you look and what should you do? We’re presenting 25 simple ideas to make your first sale online.</p>
<p>We’re encouraging you to try new tactics online, use social media, and promote in person. Take these small steps to make a leap towards your first online sale.</p>
<p style="text-align: center"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-16493" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/04/EN_25-Simple-Ideas-to-Make-your-First-Sale-Online-Image.jpg" alt="" width="580" height="230" /></p>
<p><span id="more-16492"></span></p>
<h4><span style="color: #008080">1. Tell everyone</span></h4>
<p>Start by creating your sales pitch &#8212; ensure you cover all the major points. Perfect your sales pitch while spreading the word by practicing on family and friends. After you master your sales pitch, speak <em>passionately </em>about your online store every chance you get.</p>
<h4><span style="color: #008080">2. Press Release</span></h4>
<p>Now that you’ve told everyone about your store, get the media to help spread the word. Draft a press release and send it to all local media outlets – news, magazines, and radio. Take time to write a good press release. <a href="http://service.prweb.com/learning/article/how-to-write-a-successful-news-release/" target="_blank">PRWeb </a>suggests writing with a professional voice using lots of facts but not too much jargon.</p>
<h4><span style="color: #008080">3. Contact Influential Bloggers</span></h4>
<p>Aside from traditional press, you can also reach out to influential and relevant bloggers. Ask them if they would like write a review or sample products. Be sure to research the blogger’s past reviews to better position your products. If a blogger agrees to feature your online store, make sure they link back to your site! This backlink will help your SEO!</p>
<h4><span style="color: #008080">4. Increase Traffic with SEO</span></h4>
<p>SEO, search engine optimization, is important when customers search for your online store. Optimize your site by using relevant keywords in product descriptions, category pages as well as the URL. Also be sure to fill out the Meta information for each product. Automate this by purchasing SEO module from <a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/seo-prestashop-modules/175-seo-search-engine-optimization.html" target="_blank">PrestaShop’s Official Marketplace</a>.</p>
<h4><span style="color: #008080">5. Mingle with Customers on Forums</span></h4>
<p>Aside from waiting for customers to find you, you can find them. Visit forums your target customer participates in and contribute with good content. Remember, potential customers will only read content that is valuable to them. Engage in the conversation or provide solutions to problems using your products.</p>
<h4><span style="color: #008080">6. Create a Facebook Page</span></h4>
<p>Further increase customer interaction by creating a Facebook account for your online store. Use this platform to connect with potential customers. Post <a href="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/how-to-increase-engagement-for-a-company-facebook-page/" target="_blank">engaging Facebook content</a> to get customers talking about your company and products. You can also learn about potential customers by browsing their profiles.</p>
<h4><span style="color: #008080">7. Tweet on Twitter</span></h4>
<p>“Use 140 characters to engage customers with exceptionally shareable witty content. Retweet, Favorite, &amp; Connect w/ #followers in real time!” (139/140)</p>
<p>Check out this <a href="http://www.practicalecommerce.com/articles/3991-25-Tips-for-Successful-Twitter-Engagement" target="_blank">Practical Ecommerce</a> article to learn more about successful Twitter engagement.</p>
<h4><span style="color: #008080">8. Film YouTube Videos</span></h4>
<p>Did you read directions to learn how to tie shoe laces? Doubtful. Somebody probably showed you how. Teach a topic or share a new trend with a YouTube video demonstration. Be sure you commit to making high quality videos containing great content. Check out <a href="https://econsultancy.com/blog/7919-e-commerce-product-videos-best-practice-tips" target="_blank">Econsultancy </a>for examples and best practices.</p>
<h4><span style="color: #008080">9. Inspire on Pinterest</span></h4>
<p>“Pinspire” users by creating Pinterest boards with lots of inspiration. Create a collection of complementary products to start a gift guide. Organize boards by themes so they’re easy to follow. Most importantly, be sure to include the product link in your pins for easy shopping. Develop your Pinterest Strategy with these tips from <a href="http://socialmediatoday.com/mleiter/2172691/6-tips-effective-pinterest-strategy" target="_blank">Social Media Today</a>.</p>
<h4><span style="color: #008080">10. Share images on Instagram</span></h4>
<p>Bring products to life by sharing the different way to use your product. Use images to tell a story your customers can relate to. Share the creation of your product. Get started by checking out these businesses who brought their products to life with <a href="http://business.instagram.com/blog/tagged/brand_spotlight" target="_blank">Instagram</a>.</p>
<h4><span style="color: #008080">11. Start a Blog</span></h4>
<p>Write about a topic relevant to your target customer. Tell stories about your product that makes customers fall in love or teach them something new. By drawing customers in, you increase the chance of selling the products on your online store. Be sure to include keywords in your blogpost to help your SEO!</p>
<h4><span style="color: #008080">12. Promote sales with Social Media</span></h4>
<p>Now that you have your social media outlets setup, use them to endorse your sales. Get everyone to visit your new store by offering discounts for featured products. Your followers already like your social media content; the discount might convince them to make their first purchase.</p>
<h4><span style="color: #008080">13. List Sales on Coupon Sites</span></h4>
<p>People love deals – some specifically shop on stores with sales. Promote your sales with websites that list coupons. <a href="http://biglonglists.com/105-coupon-submissions-sites" target="_blank">Submit coupons</a> to websites like <a href="http://www.retailmenot.com/coupons/submit#sthash.5O1mXcqr.dpuf" target="_blank">RetailMeNot</a>, <a href="http://www.mycoupons.com/submit-a-coupon" target="_blank">MyCoupons</a>, and <a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/coupons/" target="_blank">Reddit</a>. By promoting your deals, you increase visibility, customer volume, and eventually sales.</p>
<h4><span style="color: #008080">14. Encourage Referrals</span></h4>
<p>Even if you have the perfect product, some customers are just not ready to purchase. Don’t fret, instead encourage them to refer your products by creating and promoting a refer-a-friend program. Referrals seem more trustworthy allowing you to gain better access to potential customers. Learn more about <a href="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/the-best-ways-to-build-customer-loyalty-for-your-online-store/" target="_blank">building customer loyalty for your online store</a>.</p>
<h4><span style="color: #008080">15. Collect Emails</span></h4>
<p>Customers’ e-mails are important for marketing purposes. Obtain them by running promotions and contests. Work with websites like <a href="http://www.shefinds.com/samplesaturday/?utm_source=homepagebanner" target="_blank">SheFinds </a>that run weekly contests for readers. In exchange for an entry, they must opt in for your e-mails. You can also collect e-mails by offering a coupon code with each newsletter subscription.</p>
<h4><span style="color: #008080">16. Send Newsletters</span></h4>
<p>After you’ve collected e-mails from potential customers, stay in touch by sending newsletters. It’s a great way to convert customers. Each newsletter should either 1) <strong>remind </strong>customers about your store or 2) share a <strong>new </strong>product. Create your email marketing plan with <a href="http://static.mailchimp.com/web/guides/how-to-create-an-email-marketing-plan/package/how-to-create-an-email-marketing-plan.pdf" target="_blank">MailChimp’s guide</a>.</p>
<h4><span style="color: #008080">17. Sell in Person</span></h4>
<p>Just as physical stores use online tools to drive traffic, drive traffic to your online store with traditional advertising. Print nice fliers and business cards. Distribute them locally to interact with potential customers in person. When customers can put a face to your online store you bring in a human aspect.</p>
<h4><span style="color: #008080">18. Attend Networking Events</span></h4>
<p>Attend local events to meet and network with people to promote your business. Interact with other key players in your industry such as suppliers, distributors, and competitors. You will learn more about your industry, gain valuable networks, and meet more potential customers.</p>
<h4><span style="color: #008080">19. Leverage LinkedIn</span></h4>
<p>Keep in touch with people you meet at networking events by adding them as LinkedIn connections. Send messages periodically to build and maintain your relationship with key industry players. You can also broaden your network by asking current connections to introduce you to their connections.</p>
<h4><span style="color: #008080">20. Create an Industry Network</span></h4>
<p>Make friends with other people in your industry! Find other companies in your industry who you are not in direct competition with. In other words, look for companies with the same customers who you can address a different need for. For example, as a dog accessories retailer, work with dog sitters or dog groomers. Cross sell to each other’s client lists to double or triple your client base.</p>
<h4><span style="color: #008080">21. Get listed by Distributors</span></h4>
<p>Brand name distributors often compile lists of authorized online retailers. Request to be added to that list. Use this chance to nurture a great working relationships with your suppliers. They will be more inclined to refer clients directly to you and maybe even let you in on upcoming deals.</p>
<h4><span style="color: #008080">22. List Competitive Prices</span></h4>
<p>List your products on sites such as Google Shopping so thousands of customers can compare your prices. Competitive pricing will drive customers to your site. Increasing the number of visitors increases the chance of closing your first sale! Be sure to <a href="http://www.internetretailer.com/commentary/2012/10/22/price-wars-dont-necessarily-maximize-profits-amazon-or-ebay" target="_blank">avoid price wars</a> to ensure you are still profitable.</p>
<h4><span style="color: #008080">23. Sell on other Marketplaces</span></h4>
<p>Post your products on marketplaces such as eBay and Amazon. You can leverage their credibility to build yours while making sales. However, be aware of the listing fees marketplaces charge. Easily export products from your PrestaShop store by purchasing any of the corresponding modules from the <a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/74-marketplace-prestashop-modules" target="_blank">Official Marketplace.</a></p>
<h4><span style="color: #008080">24. Run online Ad Campaigns</span></h4>
<p>Run online ad campaigns to drive customers to your online store. Be sure your ads are relevant to your product to ensure you are using your marketing dollars wisely. Learn how to run effective <a href="http://static.googleusercontent.com/media/www.google.com/en/us/adwords/pdf/step_by_step.pdf" target="_blank">Google Ad campaigns</a> by reading their step-by-step guide.</p>
<h4><span style="color: #008080">25. Throw a Party!</span></h4>
<p>You’ve just launched an online store! That in itself is a milestone and a huge success. Celebrate by throwing a party. It’s a great time to generate content for your social media, create buzz for the press, and meet people from your industry. Most importantly, it’s a great time to thank the people who&#8217;ve helped you get this far.</p>
<p>_________________________</p>
<p>Have some tips that we should’ve included? Share them in the comments below!</p>
<p>Don’t have your online store set-up yet? Take the first step by <a href="http://www.prestashop.com/en/download" target="_blank">downloading </a>PrestaShop, the world’s best open source ecommerce software! Or <a href="http://www.prestashop.com/en/demo" target="_blank">demo </a>PrestaShop’s front and back office experience our software. Already using PrestaShop? What steps are you taking to convert your first sale? Which modules are you using? We’d love to hear from you too!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/25-simple-ideas-to-make-your-first-sale-online/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>E-Marketing Tips to Make the Most of Spring Holidays</title>
		<link>http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/e-marketing-tips-to-make-the-most-of-spring-holidays/</link>
		<comments>http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/e-marketing-tips-to-make-the-most-of-spring-holidays/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 03 Apr 2014 16:50:18 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Natalie Beigel</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Tips and Advice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=16477</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Finally, spring has sprung! It’s time for online merchants to start planting promotions and marketing plans to make the spring holiday sales bloom! According to the National Retail Federation, last year U.S consumers alone spent an estimated $17.2 billion for &#8230; <a href="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/e-marketing-tips-to-make-the-most-of-spring-holidays/" rel="nofollow" class="more-link">Read more<span class="meta-nav"></span></a>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Finally, spring has sprung! It’s time for online merchants to start planting promotions and marketing plans to make the spring holiday sales bloom! According to the <a href="http://www.nrf.com/modules.php?name=News&amp;id=557 " target="_blank">National Retail Federation</a>, last year U.S consumers alone spent an estimated $17.2 billion for Easter, $20.7 billion on Mother’s day and $13.3 billion on Father’s day.</p>
<p>That’s pretty convincing isn’t it? Let’s dive into refreshing <strong>e-marketing tips to make the most of spring holidays</strong> starting today!</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-16479" title="Emarketing Tips Spring Holidays" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/04/Emarketing-Tips-Spring-Holidays.jpg" alt="" width="531" height="239" /></p>
<p><span id="more-16477"></span><br />
We’re covering the 3 major spring holidays that are celebrated throughout the world to help you increase sales, traffic and customer satisfaction. We’ll give you tips for e-mails, social media and promotions so that you can capitalize on: Easter, Mother’s Day and Father’s Day!</p>
<h4><span style="color: #ff00ff;">Hop up Sales for Easter</span></h4>
<p><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Easter " target="_blank">Easter</a> is the first holiday in spring and families from around the world are celebrating. It’s the perfect opportunity to get creative with your marketing activities and take advantage of the wholesome cheer.</p>
<h4 style="padding-left: 30px;"><span style="color: #3366ff;">Promotions</span></h4>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">From toys to chocolate to flowers to cameras – online merchants can run Easter promotions for all of their products. Try to get creative with your promotions to reflect the holiday spirit by using clever terms such as “Free ‘Eggspress’ Shipping” or “Eggcited for Easter Sale.”</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">See how this Montreal based PrestaShop store, <a href="http://www.sweetisabelle.com/en/ " target="_blank">Sweet Isabelle</a>, uses attractive, large images to promote their Easter cookie collection on their homepage.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px; text-align: center;"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-16483" title="Sweet Isabelle Easter" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/04/Sweet-Isabelle-Easter.jpg" alt="" width="379" height="273" /></p>
<h4 style="padding-left: 30px;"><span style="color: #3366ff;">Social Media</span></h4>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">Holidays like Easter are the perfect opportunity to be both timely and relevant allowing you to increase engagement and drive new traffic to your shop! Run a contest, promote your sales or highlight products to celebrate with your fans and followers. Learn more about how to use holidays to animate your social media networks with this article by <a href="http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/social-media-marketing-for-holidays/" target="_blank">SocialMedia Examiner</a>.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">Then check out how this PrestaShop store, <a href="http://www.ohsnapboutique.com/ " target="_blank">Oh Snap! Boutique</a>, shared their Easter promo on Facebook last year.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px; text-align: center;"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-16481" title="Oh Snap Easter Sale" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/04/Oh-Snap-Easter-Sale.jpg" alt="" width="287" height="433" /></p>
<h4 style="padding-left: 30px;"><span style="color: #3366ff;">Email Marketing</span></h4>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">Reach out to your customers with a clever Easter themed e-mail. Share your Easter gift list or promote your discounts with a cute e-mail or newsletter. A good place to browse for inspiration is Pinterest – take a look at these <a href="http://www.pinterest.com/search/pins/?q=easter%20email%20marketing " target="_blank">Easter Email Marketing</a> results.</p>
<h4><span style="color: #ff00ff;">Mother’s Day &amp; Father’s Day</span></h4>
<p>Both Mother’s Day and Father’s Day are two of the most important e-commerce sales holidays every year. Make sure to prepare in advance and start your sales and marketing strategies early!</p>
<h4 style="padding-left: 30px;"><span style="color: #3366ff;">Promotions</span></h4>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">Both of these holidays are perfect opportunities to add a featured product page on your online shop. Create pages with products customized for moms and dads such as: “50 Mother’s Day Gifts under $50” or “Perfect Father’s Day Gifts.” The easier your customers can find the perfect gift, the more likely they are to make a purchase. These types of pages will also greatly improve your SEO efforts and help you rank higher on search engine results.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"><a href="http://www.odealarose.com/" target="_blank">Ode a la Rose</a> is a great example of a PrestaShop store that used homepage banners to drive traffic to their Mother’s Day product pages last year.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px; text-align: center;"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-16480" title="Ode a la rose Mothers Day" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/04/Ode-a-la-rose-Mothers-Day.jpg" alt="" width="355" height="284" /></p>
<h4 style="padding-left: 30px;"><span style="color: #3366ff;">Social Media</span></h4>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">Run a social media campaign that would make mom and dad proud! Start promoting these two holidays early to increase awareness and be the first to remind your customers that it’s just around the corner. Mother’s Day and Father’s Day tends to be a sentimental holiday so it’s a great time to run a social media contest. Ask your fans and followers to post photos with a caption about “Why their mom/dad is the best!” Having customers share this type of content will help you build a closer relationship.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">Take a look at these<a href="http://www.likeable.com/blog/2013/05/4-brands-that-did-mothers-day-campaigns-right/" target="_blank"> 4 Brands that did their Mother’s Day Campaign Right</a> on Likeable.com.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">Oreo India ran a brilliant social media campaign called “Wish for Dad.” Genius! See more amazing <a href="http://www.business2community.com/facebook/9-cool-fathers-day-facebook-campaigns-2013-0524752#!BKyzE " target="_blank">Father’s Day Facebook Campaigns</a> for some great ideas.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px; text-align: center;"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-16482" title="Oreos Fathers Day Campaign" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/04/Oreos-Fathers-Day-Campaign.jpg" alt="" width="419" height="395" /></p>
<h4 style="padding-left: 30px;"><span style="color: #3366ff;">Email Marketing</span></h4>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">Inform your customers about the amazing deals your running through an effective e-mail campaign. Keep in mind that Mother’s and Father’s Day also includes uncles, aunts, mothers-in-law, fathers-in-law, brothers, sisters… remind your customers that you have the perfect gift for everyone waiting on your shop.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">Include some helpful advice such as “where to take mom for mother’s day?” or “what does dad really want to do on father’s day?” –including this type of content in your e-mail will increase customer loyalty and discretely improve your future open rates. This article from Email Design Review will inspire you with their article on “<a href="http://www.emaildesignreview.com/email-industry-insight/fathers-day-emails-to-the-rescue-1536/ " target="_blank">Father’s Day Emails to the Rescue</a>.”</p>
<h4><span style="color: #ff00ff;">Spring Up Sales Today!</span></h4>
<p>These examples should help get you started for the spring holidays. Make sure you’re prepared for all the big shopping dates this year with our 2014 <a href="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/important-shopping-dates-for-e-commerce-merchants-2014/" target="_blank">Ecommerce Shopping Dates calendar</a>.</p>
<p>Want to make more money selling online? Start your FREE <a href="http://www.prestashop.com/en/download " target="_blank">PrestaShop</a> store today and sell more this spring!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/e-marketing-tips-to-make-the-most-of-spring-holidays/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>We’re hiring Country Managers! You could represent PrestaShop in your home country!</title>
		<link>http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/were-hiring-you-could-represent-prestashop-in-your-home-country/</link>
		<comments>http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/were-hiring-you-could-represent-prestashop-in-your-home-country/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 03 Apr 2014 13:25:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Natalie Beigel</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[PrestaShop News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=16428</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Are you driven, passionate and curious? Do you have refreshing ideas to bring to the table? Think you can keep up with our fast paced work environment? If this sounds like you, then we have the perfect job opportunity to &#8230; <a href="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/were-hiring-you-could-represent-prestashop-in-your-home-country/" rel="nofollow" class="more-link">Read more<span class="meta-nav"></span></a>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Are you driven, passionate and curious? Do you have refreshing ideas to bring to the table? Think you can keep up with our fast paced work environment? If this sounds like you, then we have the perfect job opportunity to satisfy your entrepreneurial thirst!</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-16431" title="EN_Country Manager Banner" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/04/EN_Country-Manager-Banner.jpg" alt="" width="580" height="195" /></p>
<p><span id="more-16428"></span></p>
<p>At PrestaShop, we always <span style="color: #515151;"><strong>THINK global</strong></span> but <strong><span style="color: #515151;">ACT local</span></strong>. That’s why, in efforts to further strengthen our international presence on a<em> local level</em>, we’re looking to hire <span style="color: #515151;"><strong>9 Country Managers</strong></span> in: Brazil, Canada, UK, Germany, Italy, Spain, Poland, Russia and Benelux.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-16432" title="EN_Countries" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/04/EN_Countries.jpg" alt="" width="269" height="135" /></p>
<p>As a country manager, you will represent PrestaShop in your respective country with a mission to increase brand awareness, multiply our user base and identify strategic local partnerships to position PrestaShop as your country’s <span style="color: #515151;"><em>preferred</em> </span>e-commerce solution.</p>
<p>Why wait? Take advantage of this <span style="color: #515151;"><em><strong>once in a lifetime</strong></em></span> opportunity! Learn all about this position in our <a href="http://www.prestashop.com/en/country-manager-job" target="_blank">job description</a> and apply today!</p>
<p><span style="color: #515151;"><strong>Join a Family of Innovators</strong></span><br />
PrestaShop’s entrepreneurial team is made up of e-commerce enthusiasts that are committed to the success and profitability of our online merchants. Headquartered in Paris and Miami, we work relentlessly to empower our users and strengthen our position as the world’s leading e-commerce software. We believe having fun on the job is a necessity to promote creativity and innovation. We hire driven, passionate and curious individuals who can keep up with our fast paced work environment and bring refreshing ideas to the table. We encourage growth within the company, reward initiative and always motivate our team to dream big.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/were-hiring-you-could-represent-prestashop-in-your-home-country/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>6</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>PrestaShop World Tour: In Auckland with Linden Leaves!</title>
		<link>http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/prestashop-world-tour-in-auckland-with-linden-leaves/</link>
		<comments>http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/prestashop-world-tour-in-auckland-with-linden-leaves/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2014 14:24:44 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Quentin Audrain</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[PrestaShop World Tour]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=16463</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Now a days, every brick and mortar store is joining the world of e-commerce and PrestaShop has helped many merchants do so. In fact, no matter what you go in New Zealand, you’ll hear all about local mom and pop &#8230; <a href="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/prestashop-world-tour-in-auckland-with-linden-leaves/" rel="nofollow" class="more-link">Read more<span class="meta-nav"></span></a>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Now a days, every brick and mortar store is joining the world of e-commerce and PrestaShop has helped many merchants do so. In fact, no matter what you go in New Zealand, you’ll hear all about local mom and pop shops starting to sell online.</p>
<p>For others, they saw the value of selling online a long time ago – like <a href="http://lindenleaves.com.au/" target="_blank">Linden Leaves</a> who recently migrated their shop to PrestaShop.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-16464" title="EN_Linden Leaves" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/04/EN_Linden-Leaves.jpg" alt="" width="585" height="372" /></p>
<p><span id="more-16463"></span></p>
<p>Linden Leaves is a well-known and established brand in New Zealand, exporting their products all over Oceania and Asia. New Zealanders love their hand made products and respect for the environment. This is why their brick and mortar store is always crowded and the main reason they needed a strong e-commerce solution to support their needs.</p>
<p>Watch the video and meet Juliet, who tells us all about how their online store is doing in New Zealand!<br />
<iframe src="//player.vimeo.com/video/90748455" frameborder="0" width="500" height="281"></iframe></p>
<p>Follow us to our next stop: <span style="color: #008080;"><strong>AUSTRALIA</strong></span>!</p>
<p>Join the PrestaShop World Tour conversation with hashtag <span style="color: #000000;"><strong>#PSWorldTour</strong></span> and follow the journey via <a href="https://twitter.com/PrestaShop" target="_blank">Twitter</a>, <a href="http://instagram.com/prestashop#" target="_blank">Instagram</a> and <a href="https://www.facebook.com/prestashop" target="_blank">Facebook</a>!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/prestashop-world-tour-in-auckland-with-linden-leaves/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Sell More Online: 8 Tips for your Product Descriptions</title>
		<link>http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/sell-more-online-8-tips-for-your-product-descriptions/</link>
		<comments>http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/sell-more-online-8-tips-for-your-product-descriptions/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2014 16:23:09 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Julie Liu</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Tips and Advice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=16401</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[For most online merchants, product descriptions may seem like a no brainer, an obvious necessity to selling online. However, too many merchants are missing out on sales and traffic as a result of poor quality product descriptions or even worse &#8230; <a href="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/sell-more-online-8-tips-for-your-product-descriptions/" rel="nofollow" class="more-link">Read more<span class="meta-nav"></span></a>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>For most online merchants, product descriptions may seem like a no brainer, an obvious necessity to selling online. However, too many merchants are missing out on sales and traffic as a result of poor quality product descriptions or even worse – copying the manufacturer’s generic content.</p>
<p>The good news, well-written product descriptions can give you the competitive advantage, helping you rank higher on search engines and increasing your bottom line. Draw in customers and sell more online with these must-read 8 tips for your product descriptions.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-16405" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/04/EN_8-Tips-for-Product-Descriptions.jpg" alt="" width="580" height="230" /></p>
<h4><span id="more-16401"></span></h4>
<h4><span style="color: #f4a460">1) Wear your Customer’s Shoes</span></h4>
<p>Figuratively speaking, that is. No matter what you’re selling online, you should have a very good understanding of your target customer. Reflect that in your voice, language, and style. I strongly recommend creating an online persona, an imaginary customer, who absolutely loves to buy your products.</p>
<p>This Forbes article <a href="http://www.forbes.com/sites/groupthink/2013/07/03/online-personas-the-key-to-converting-customers/" target="_blank">“Online Personas: The Key to Converting Customers”</a> will help you fully understand your target audience. As a result, you’ll write unique product descriptions that effectively converts visitors into paying customers.</p>
<h4><span style="color: #f4a460">2) Persuade with Benefits</span></h4>
<p>Now that you are familiar with your online personas, you know which benefits will sway your customers to make a purchase. Highlight benefits by addressing questions such as: How is your product better than the competitor? How can your product solve a problem for your customer?<br />
Check out how this PrestaShop store, <a href="http://www.gretelhome.com/areaware/913-diamond-box-in-black.html" target="_blank">Gretel Home</a>, presents the benefits of their Diamond Box to appeal to customers.</p>
<p style="text-align: center"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-16408" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/04/store-2.png" alt="" width="550" height="400" /></p>
<p>In just 3 sentences, Gretel Home was able to point out 6 different benefits: multiple functionality, safe, seamless, perfect gift, inexpensive, and small. They also used sensory words to touch the soft spots of their customers – hold that thought, we’ll talk more about sensory words in just a bit.</p>
<h4><span style="color: #f4a460">3) Tell Stories</span></h4>
<p>Tap into your customers’ imagination. Transport them to a place and time where they see themselves using your product. Start a story and let customers fill in the details wherever they can relate. For some inspiration, look at how this PrestaShop store, Planete Chocolat, tells a story that stars their Box of Easter Chocolates.</p>
<p style="text-align: center"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-16407" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/04/store-3.png" alt="" width="634" height="259" /></p>
<p><a href="http://www.planetechocolat.com/en/easter-chocolates/867-a-box-of-easter-chocolates.html" target="_blank">Planete Chocolat</a> created a product description that puts the product in the customer’s life. By using just the right amount of details they planted the seed of a story. They then let customers fill in the details of a perfect Easter morning.</p>
<h4><span style="color: #f4a460">4) Stimulate Your Customer’s Senses</span></h4>
<p>Let your customers feel. Do this by using sensory words that appeal to any of our five senses. Easily appeal to auditory senses with onomatopoeias, words that imitate the sound it makes. Some examples? Clocks tick, cell phones buzz, jewelry jangles and steaks sizzle. Each item you read made a sound you can hear.</p>
<p>As you stimulate each sense, you bring another dimension of your product to life. Want to feel the Nourishing Body Milk on your skin? Read the product description from this PrestaShop ecommerce site, <a href="//tahitiansecrets.com/en/-beauty-care-/39-lait-nourrisant-10-200-ml-3458517511255.html" target="_blank">Tahitian Secrets</a>:</p>
<p style="text-align: center"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-16409" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/04/store-4.png" alt="" width="548" height="317" /></p>
<p>Most people know what velvety, silky, and smooth textures feel like. These descriptions allow customers to literally feel the product through their screen.</p>
<h4><span style="color: #f4a460">5) Details, Details, Details.</span></h4>
<p>What are the FAQ’s for your product? Product descriptions should answer all the basic questions a customers would ask. Start by answering a relevant question from each of these 5 categories:</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px">• <strong>Who</strong> – Who needs it? Who is it made for? Who made it?<br />
• <strong>What</strong> – What is the product? What features does it have? What is it for?<br />
• <strong>Where</strong> – Where is it made? Where should it be used?<br />
• <strong>Why</strong> – Why do customers need it? Why it is better? Why purchase it?<br />
• <strong>When</strong> – When was it made? When should they replace it?</p>
<p>Answer as many as possible while staying relevant. (By addressing commonly asked questions in product descriptions, you also save time on customer service.) See how this PrestaShop store, <a href="http://www.whatgoesaroundnyc.com/shop/luxury-shoulder-bags/21512-60CH-85668.html" target="_blank">WhatGoesAroundNYC</a> describes their Vintage Chanel Bag:</p>
<p style="text-align: center"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-16410" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/04/store-5-2.png" alt="" width="545" height="347" /></p>
<p>As a Vintage Luxury goods retailers, it is especially important to include the product’s condition. By listing the condition of each part, it shows that the product has been carefully inspected which increases trust – making a customer more likely to make the purchase.</p>
<h4><span style="color: #f4a460">6) Use Original, Keyword Rich Content</span></h4>
<p>SEO is all the rage! With most customers using search to find products, it is important to rank high in these search results. Increase your page rank by using keywords to improve your SEO. First step? Do away with generic manufacturer descriptions. With so many online merchants already using them, duplicating them on your site hurts your SEO.</p>
<p>Instead, view manufacturer descriptions as inspiration for your original content. But before you start writing, find relevant keywords for your product. <a href="http://adwords.google.com/keywordplanner" target="_blank">Google Adwords</a>’s Keyword Planner is a great way to start. You can also check out alternatives suggested by <a href="http://socialmediatoday.com/pamdyer/2039406/10-great-alternatives-google-keyword-research-tool" target="_blank">Social Media Today</a> such as Keyword Eye. Here’s their suggested top 10 keywords for “sunglasses”:</p>
<p style="text-align: center"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-16437" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/04/store-61.png" alt="" width="526" height="398" /></p>
<p>As you write descriptions, pick a few relevant keywords to include. Each original, keyword rich product description you write will help to increase your SEO.</p>
<h4><span style="color: #f4a460">7) Be Easy on the Eyes</span></h4>
<p>It’s easy to get carried away with writing product descriptions. There are so many details you can include. Make sure your product descriptions are displayed in a format that is easy to read. Break up large paragraphs with bullet points. This allows customers to quickly scan through and find what they need. If you have lots to say, create both a short and long description. Check out how this PrestaShop bike store, <a href="http://www.btwin.com/en/leisure-mtb/17410-btwin-rockrider-340-c4-mtb.html" target="_blank">BTWIN </a>extensively details a product in a reader-friendly format.</p>
<p style="text-align: center"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-16404" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/04/store-7a.png" alt="" width="607" height="282" /></p>
<p style="text-align: center"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-16402" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/04/STORE-7b.png" alt="" width="560" height="496" /></p>
<h4><span style="color: #f4a460">8) Let Customers Review</span></h4>
<p>Want free and original descriptions for your products? Look no further than product reviews. Content written by other shoppers seem more trustworthy because lying does not benefit them. Customer reviews can also provide information from a user’s perspective, addressing questions online merchants often forget.<br />
See how these customer reviews help <a href="http://www.justfab.fr/index.cfm?action=shop.viewproduct&amp;tab=shoe&amp;ha=8636E4A896FA6B8F92D455DCDDDFFB1E&amp;pid=638086" target="_blank">JustFab FR</a>, another PrestaShop merchant, with describing their product.</p>
<p style="text-align: center"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-16403" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/04/store-8.png" alt="" width="510" height="422" /></p>
<p>By addressing concerns about height and comfort, the customer reviews add helpful information for customers. Their praise for the product also helps to convert shoppers. The unique content in customer reviews helps with SEO!</p>
<p>Which of these 8 tips will you use to improve your product descriptions? Share the ones you&#8217;ve crafted in the comments below!</p>
<p>___________________</p>
<p>Don’t have an online store yet? Ready to take your ecommerce site to the next level?<a href="http://www.prestashop.com/en/download" target="_blank"> Download PrestaShop</a> – the best ecommerce software with simple yet powerful content management capabilities and hundreds of features – and start selling online today!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/sell-more-online-8-tips-for-your-product-descriptions/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>5 Creative Online Business Ideas – Ecommerce Inspiration</title>
		<link>http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/5-creative-online-business-ideas-ecommerce-inspiration/</link>
		<comments>http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/5-creative-online-business-ideas-ecommerce-inspiration/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 27 Mar 2014 13:57:48 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Natalie Beigel</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Success Stories]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=16355</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[It’s true. The online business market is oversaturated with the most popular and trendy products – but what about those entrepreneurs that didn’t jump on the “just a fad” bandwagon? These brilliant innovators are the reasons you ask yourself: Why &#8230; <a href="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/5-creative-online-business-ideas-ecommerce-inspiration/" rel="nofollow" class="more-link">Read more<span class="meta-nav"></span></a>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="color: #000000;">It’s true. The online business market is oversaturated with the most popular and trendy products – but what about those entrepreneurs that didn’t jump on the “just a fad” bandwagon? These brilliant innovators are the reasons you ask yourself: <em>Why didn’t I think of that?</em></span></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;">I want to introduce you to <strong>5 creative online business ideas – ecommerce inspiration</strong> – for those <em>hungry for imagination and innovation</em>. After all, we live in a world where bringing a business to life is simple, once you find that big idea.</span></p>
<p><img class="alignleft  wp-image-16356" title="EN_Creative Online Business Ideas Blog Post" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/03/EN_Creative-Online-Business-Ideas-Blog-Post.png" alt="" width="531" height="225" /><br />
<span id="more-16355"></span></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;">Of course, just coming up with a product to sell isn’t going to guarantee success. Put your idea to the test when you read my article on</span> <a href="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/how-to-find-the-right-products-to-sell-online/ " target="_blank">How to Find the Right Products to Sell Online</a>.</p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;">Now, let’s meet 5 online businesses that transformed their genius ideas into a successfully running PrestaShop online store.</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h4 style="text-align: center;"><span style="color: #691578;"><strong>Madame Choup</strong></span></h4>
<h6 style="text-align: center;"><span style="color: #000000;">“When fashion invites itself in the kitchen”</span></h6>
<p style="text-align: left;"><img style="border: 0pt none; float: left; padding-right: 10px; padding-bottom: 10px;" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/03/Madame_Choup.png" alt="" /><span style="color: #000000;"><span style="color: #000000;"><strong>What they sell:</strong></span> <a href="http://www.madamechoup.com/ " target="_blank">Madame Choup</a> sells unique 1950’s inspired cooking aprons. Aprons are a timeless product meaning that they aren’t just a trend. They took a unique approach by creating fashion forward aprons that women love to wear. Madame Choup is a PrestaShop award winning site with 8,000 Facebook fans.</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img class=" wp-image-16368 aligncenter" title="Madame Choup Products" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/03/Madame-Choup-Products.jpg" alt="" width="602" height="297" /></p>
<h4 style="text-align: center;"><span style="color: #691578;"><strong>Draw me a Song</strong></span></h4>
<h6 style="text-align: center;"><span style="color: #000000;">“Fusion between music and visual art”</span></h6>
<p><img style="border: 0pt none; float: left; padding-right: 10px; padding-bottom: 10px;" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/03/logo.jpg" alt="" /><span style="color: #000000;"><strong><span style="color: #000000;">What they sell:</span></strong> <a href="http://drawmeasong.com/ " target="_blank">Draw Me a Song</a> sells colorful and original illustrations of some of the most famous song lyrics in the music industry. They are the winners of the Deutsche Bank Creative Award in February 2011 and semi-finalist in the MIT Business Plan Competition in February 2012.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-16363" title="Draw me a song products" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/03/Draw-me-a-song-products.jpg" alt="" width="498" height="445" /></p>
<h4 style="text-align: center;"><span style="color: #691578;">The Phobia Shop</span></h4>
<h6 style="text-align: center;"><span style="color: #000000;">“Laugh at your fears and embrace them”</span></h6>
<p><img style="border: 0pt none; float: left; padding-right: 10px; padding-bottom: 10px;" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/03/logo-phobia-shop.jpg" alt="" /><span style="color: #000000;"><strong>What they sell:</strong></span> <a href="http://www.thephobiashop.com/ " target="_blank">The Phobia Shop</a> <span style="color: #000000;">sells original t-shirts designed with your funkiest fears in mind. Since every human can relate to phobias, the purpose of this online store is for people to have fun and laugh at their own fears. The concept was created by the company President, Power Capote, a nurse who realized that there was a huge market for this product and believed that the world could use some extra smiles and cool t-shirts.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-16372" title="Phobia Shop Products" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/03/Phobia-Shop-Products.jpg" alt="" width="588" height="321" /></p>
<h4 style="text-align: center;"><span style="color: #691578;">Eatingtools</span></h4>
<h6 style="text-align: center;"><span style="color: #000000;">“eat. cook. explore.”</span></h6>
<p><img style="border: 0pt none; float: left; padding-right: 10px; padding-bottom: 10px;" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/03/logo-1.jpg" alt="" /><strong><span style="color: #000000;">What they sell:</span></strong> <a href="http://www.eatingtools.com/ " target="_blank">Eatingtools</a><span style="color: #000000;">, based in Brooklyn, is an online store for the food-loving visionaries selling top quality eating and cooking tools. Many are handmade, some are one-of-a-kind creations and others come from some of the world’s top production companies. Their unique and modern site makes perfect use of beautiful, large imagery.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-16364" title="Eating Tools Products" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/03/Eating-Tools-Products-1024x694.jpg" alt="" width="526" height="356" /></p>
<h4 style="text-align: center;"><span style="color: #691578;">My Little Party</span></h4>
<h6 style="text-align: center;"><span style="color: #000000;">“Your Perfect Party”</span></h6>
<p><img style="border: 0pt none; float: left; padding-right: 10px; padding-bottom: 10px;" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/03/My-little-party.jpg" alt="" /><strong><span style="color: #000000;">What they sell:</span></strong> <a href="http://www.mylittleparty.es/ " target="_blank">My Little Party</a> <span style="color: #000000;">sells original and stylish party products to add that extra festive touch. The shop is based in Spain and sells everything from decorations to utensils bringing unique products from the United States, UK and Australia. My Little Party has been featured in Elle, Marie Clair and Vogue.</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-16370" title="My Little Party Products" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/03/My-Little-Party-Products.jpg" alt="" width="544" height="204" /></p>
<h4 style="text-align: center;"><span style="color: #691578;">Feeling Inspired?</span></h4>
<p>Set your online store up for success with our <a href="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/how-to-create-an-online-store-10-steps-to-write-your-business-plan/ " target="_blank">10 Steps to Writing an Ecommerce Business Plan</a>.</p>
<p>Then, take advantage of PrestaShop’s beautiful default template and brilliant back-end to grow a booming business like the stores above! <a href="http://www.prestashop.com/en/download" target="_blank">Download PrestaShop</a> for free today or try out the <a href="http://www.prestashop.com/en/demo" target="_blank">demo</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/5-creative-online-business-ideas-ecommerce-inspiration/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>5</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>PrestaShop World Tour: New Zealand Flower Shop Auckland</title>
		<link>http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/prestashop-world-tour-new-zealand-flower-shop-auckland/</link>
		<comments>http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/prestashop-world-tour-new-zealand-flower-shop-auckland/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 26 Mar 2014 13:48:10 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Quentin Audrain</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[PrestaShop World Tour]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=16343</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Here we are in New Zealand, a completely different e-commerce experience from the other cities we have visited so far. New Zealand has a great sense of pride for local businesses and there is nothing more important than going out &#8230; <a href="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/prestashop-world-tour-new-zealand-flower-shop-auckland/" rel="nofollow" class="more-link">Read more<span class="meta-nav"></span></a>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Here we are in New Zealand, a completely different e-commerce experience from the other cities we have visited so far.</p>
<p>New Zealand has a great sense of pride for local businesses and there is nothing more important than going out to a local shop to buy what you need. New Zealanders love the outdoors and interacting with their community.</p>
<p><img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-16344" title="EN_New Zealand PrestaShop World Tour" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/03/EN_New-Zealand-PrestaShop-World-Tour.jpg" alt="" width="585" height="329" /><br />
<span id="more-16343"></span></p>
<p>So, what’s the e-commerce market like? For the younger generations, they are active online and mobile shoppers.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img class="wp-image-16345 aligncenter" title="Flower Shop Auckland" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2014/03/Flower-Shop-Auckland.jpg" alt="" width="464" height="310" /></p>
<p>Watch the video to meet Kerry and Francis from <a href="http://flowershopauckland.co.nz/" target="_blank">Flower Shop Auckland</a>, a recently launched PrestaShop store selling flowers for every occasion!</p>
<p><iframe src="//player.vimeo.com/video/90115697" frameborder="0" width="500" height="281"></iframe></p>
<p><a href="http://vimeo.com/90115697">Ecommerce WorldTour &#8211; Flower Shop Auckland, New Zealand</a> from <a href="http://vimeo.com/prestashop">PrestaShop</a> on <a href="https://vimeo.com">Vimeo</a>.</p>
<p>Join the PrestaShop World Tour conversation with hashtag <span style="color: #000000;"><strong>#PSWorldTour</strong></span> and follow the journey via <a href="https://twitter.com/PrestaShop" target="_blank">Twitter</a>, <a href="http://instagram.com/prestashop#" target="_blank">Instagram</a> and <a href="https://www.facebook.com/prestashop" target="_blank">Facebook</a>!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/prestashop-world-tour-new-zealand-flower-shop-auckland/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>

<!-- Performance optimized by W3 Total Cache. Learn more: http://www.w3-edge.com/wordpress-plugins/

Minified using disk: basic
Page Caching using disk: enhanced
Object Caching 829/977 objects using disk: basic

Served from: www.prestashop.com @ 2014-04-12 19:56:02 -->